Brecht, Arnold; Papers ger024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1905-1976; 2; 319 file folders
  - General correspondence, 2.2
    - Ohmann, Fritz Ernst, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Oldenburg, Otto, 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Oppen, Beate Ruhm von, 1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Oppenheim, Felix, 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - P -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
    - Paeschke, Hans (Merkur), 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Palitsch, Alice, 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Paul, Julius, 1958 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Pelckmann, Horst, 1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Peltzer, Artur, 1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Peltzer, Bert, 1938-1939 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Peltzer, Helmut, 1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Pennock, J. Roland, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton (American Defense, Harvard Group), 1943-1944 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Peters, Hans, 1949; 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Pfuhl, Georg & Erika, 1915-1968 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Pfuhl, Sophia, 1968-1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Pikart, Eberhard, 1955-1956; 1965; 1970 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - R. Piper et Co. Verlag (Walter Hinderer), 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Planck, Erwin, 1934 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Plessner, Monika, 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Poetzsch-Heffter, 1935 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Pogge-von Strandmann, Hartmut, 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Pollock, James K., 1945-1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Popitz, Heinrich, 1972; Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Posner, Ernst, 1944 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Pound, Roscoe, 1939-1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Public Personnel Review (J. J. Donovan), 1950-1951 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - R -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Radbruch, Gustav, 1939-1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Radbruch, Lydia, 1950-1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Rademacher, Hans, 1941; 1951; 1969 (death notice) (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Radin, Max (California Law Review), 1939-1940 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Radio Bremen, 1959-1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Rauers, Friedrich, 1953-1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Recaséns-Siches, Luis, 1955-1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Redslob, Edwin, 1948-1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Reed, Edward A., 1970 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Reed, Ruth Lawrence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Rempel, Rudolf, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Richter, Thomas J., 1951-1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Ridgeway, George, 1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Rieppel, Eva, 1969-1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Riesman, David, 1939; 1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Riezler, Kurt, 1943; 1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Riezler, Walter, 1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Riggs, Fred W., 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Rintelen, Paul & Anita, 1955-1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Robinson, James A., 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Rodriguez, Fausto E. (Luis Recaséns-Siches Festschrift), 1974-1975 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Rogers, Lindsay, 1937-1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Roothbert, Albert & Toni, 1944-1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Rothfels, Hans, 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Rüstow, Alexander, 1952-1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Rüstow, Lorena, 1963-1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Runde, Wolfgang & Antje, 1954-1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Rutz, Consuelo, 1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - S -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Samuel, Arthur, 1964-1967 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Schaeffer, Hans & Eva, 1966-1967 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Schaffner, Joseph Halle, 1939; 1951-1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Schaffner, Ruth, 1967-1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Schairer, Reinhold, 1941-1942 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Schatz, Rudolf, 1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Scherk, Gerhard & Elizabeth, 1950-1969 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Schiffer, Eugen, 1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Schlesinger, M., 1970-1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Schlesinger, Rudolf B. (Columbia Law Review), 1941 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Schmidt, Eberhard, 1960-1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Schmidt, Hans Martin, 1950 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Schmidt, Robert H., 1959; 1963 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Schmidt-Klugmann, Annemarie, 1971-1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Schmidt-Römhild, Georg, 1949 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Schneider, Hans, 1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Schönwandt, M., 1957-1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Schroeder, Hans, 1944-1966 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Schröter, Walter, 1962; 1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Schüller, Richard, 1970 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Schulz, Gerhard, 1957-1965 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Schulze, Hagen, 1968-1975 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Schwenk, Walter, 1961-1962 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Schwertfeger, Bernhard, 1950 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Seligman, Edwin R., 1934-1935 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Severing, Carl, 1950-1951 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Shuster, George N., 1944 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Siebeck, Hans Goerg (J.C.B. Mohr, Paul Siebeck), 1963; 1975 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Sösemann, Bernd W., 1970-1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Sollmann, William, 1937-1951 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Sontheimer, Kurt, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Spangenberg, Berthold (Nymphenburger Verlagshandlung), 1959-1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - SPD (Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands), 1952; 1958 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Speyer, Emil John, 1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Spiegelberg, Ernst (Ernest) & Marie-Louise, 1943-1976 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Spranger, Eduard, 1954-1958 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Staatslexikon (Herder Verlag), 1957; 1959 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Stadelmeyer, Peter (Goethe House, NY), 1967; 1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Stampfer, Friedrich, 1945-1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Stern, Frederick M., 1945; 1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Sternberger, Dolf, 1955-1968 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Stinnes, Edmund H., 1942-1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Stoke, Harold W., 1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Stolper, Gustav, 1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Stolper, Toni, 1956-1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Stourzh, Gerald, 1964-1965 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Strauss, Leo, 1941-1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Strauss, Walter, 1950; 1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Strausz-Hupé, Robert, 1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Stuttgarter Zeitung, 1959-1960 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Süddeutsche Zeitung, 1950; 1955 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Süddeutscher Rundfunk, 1956 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - T - V -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Tillich, Paul, 1943; 1959 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Tillich, Hannah, 1965 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Topitsch, Ernst, 1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Ulich, Robert, 1934; 1941-1944 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - University of Heidelberg (Universität Heidelberg), 1947-1963 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - University of Mainz (Universität Mainz), 1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Unkelbach, Helmut, 1956-1968 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Vagts, Alfred, 1968 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Valentin, 1942; 1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Valle, Raymond, 1974 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Verdross, Alfred, 1962 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Vermehren, Kurt, 1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Viehweg, Theodor, 1963 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Voegelin, Eric / Voegelin Festschrift, 1946-1962 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Vogelstein, T.M., 1940 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Vogt, Martin, 1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Volkamer, Gustav, 1955 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - W - Z -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1943; 1958-1967 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Warburg, Eric M., 1946-1975 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Warburg, Max, 1936-1944 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Warburg, Ingrid, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Weber, Alfred, 1953 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Weber, Dieter, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Weil, Agnes (Mrs. Sumner), 1964-1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Weishaupt, Paul, 1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Weiszäcker, Carl Friedrich von, 1975 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Weltner (née Reuter), Maria (Mia), 1951-1962 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Wever, Karl, 1948-1960 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Weyland, Hans, 1969 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Wheeler-Bennett, Sir John W., 1937; 1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - White, Leonard D., 1936-1945; 1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Widder, Erwin, 1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Wiese, Leopold von, 1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Wildenmann, Rudolf, 1975 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Williams, Pierce, 1939 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Wilson, Francis G., 1946-1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Winckelmann, Johannes, 1958-1967 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Wissell, Rudolf, 1956 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Wolf, Erik, 1955-1959 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Wolfers, Arnold, 1944-1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Wolff, Ernst, 1950-1951 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Wolman, Benjamin B. (Cross Currents of Our Times), 1967 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation / Woodrow Wilson Award, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Wright, Benjamin, 1946-1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Wright, Quincy, 1949-1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Zahn, Karl von, 1938 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Zahn-Harnack, Agnes von, 1949 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - "Important letters received". Transcripts, 1934-1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Correspondence concerning published articles, 1934-1957; 1966 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Correspondence concerning lecture engagements, 1933-1967 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Students: A -- B, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Students: C -- F, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Students: Eugene T. Ferraro, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Students: G -- J, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Students: K -- L, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
    - Students: M -- R, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Students: S -- Z, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Students, other, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - Correspondence with U.S. government officials, 2.3
    - U.S. government officials, 1936-1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1949; 1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Adams, Sherman, 1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Appleby, Paul H., 1941-1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Carter, Jimmy & Rosalynn, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Clay, Lucius D., 1945-1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1934-1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1937-1950 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Fulbright, J. W., 1952-1953 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1948 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1943 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Jessup, Philip C., 1946-1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Jump, W. A., 1939-1945 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Lewis, Geoffrey W., 1952-1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Murphy, Robert, 1947-1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Patton, George S., 1945 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1944; 1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
    - Stone, Donald C., 1940-1960 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
    - Wertheimer, Egon Ranshofen, 1942-1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - New York City/State officials, 1938-1942; 1963 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - United Nations officials, 1946-1947; 1950-1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - War Department members (Allen L. Edwards, Paul M. A. Linebarger), 1942-1959 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - OMGUS (Office of Military Government for Germany), including, 2.7
    - Glaser, Comstock, 1939-1951 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Jones, Howard P., 1943-1946 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Karsen, Fritz, 1943-1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
  - OMGUS (Office of Military Government for Germany), including, 2.8
    - Landin, Harold W., 1948 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Tuthill, John & Erna, 1945-1948; 1962 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Warner, Adolphe J., 1947 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Wells, Roger H., 1947; 1952; 1962 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
  - HICOG (High Commissioner for Germany), including, 2.9
    - Conant, James B., 1940; 1952-1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Dillinger, L. E., 1950 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Hunter, David R., 1949 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Mason, John B., 1951-1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
  - HICOG (High Commissioner for Germany), including, 2.10
    - McCloy, John J., 1950-1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Stone, Shepard, 1945-1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Wolfsperger, Ellsworth, 1949-1951 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Zink, Harold, 1946-1950 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
  - Embassies ( Canada, England, India), 1943-1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
  - German Bundestag members visit to U.S., 1950 May (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
  - German Consul General, New York, including, 2.13
    - Curtius, Klaus, 1964-1971 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Federer, Georg, 1959-1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Krauss, Georg, 1955 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
  - German Consul General, New York, including, 2.14
    - Posadowsky-Werner, Harald Graf von, 1971-1973 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Rhamm, Ulrich von, 1962-1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Riesser, Hans E., 1932; 1951; 1966-1968 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Schmidt-Schlegel, Philipp, 1969 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
  - German Consul General, Washington, including, 2.15
    - Grewe, Wilhelm G., 1955-1961 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Knappstein, Heinrich, 1964 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Krekeler, Heinz L., 1951-1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Pauls, Rolf, 1970; 1972 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
  - Correspondence with German public officials, 2.16
    - Correspondence with German public officials, 1935-1965 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Adenauer, Konrad, 1948-1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Anders, Georg, 1955-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Boettcher, Erich (Bürgermeister von Lübeck), 1951-1968 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Brandt, Willy, 1957-1976 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Braun, Otto, 1932-1955 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Brüning, Heinrich, 1937-1966 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Ebert, Friedrich, 1921-1922 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Ebert, Karl, 1955 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Erhard, Ludwig, 1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Friedensburg, Ferdinand, 1935-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Gerstenmaier, Eugen (Bundespräsident), 1959; 1961 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Heinemann, Gustav W., 1967-1970 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Heuss, Theodor, 1948-1966 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Kaiser, Jakob, 1950-1956 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Kohl, Helmut, 1976 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Kroeger, Hans, 1949-1954 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Lex, Ritter von, 1951-1957 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Löbe, Paul, 1934-1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Lübke, Heinrich, 1959; 1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Oppler, 1951-1952 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Pünder, Hermann, 1948-1956 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Scheel, Walter, 1976 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Schmid, Carlo, 1952; 1974 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Schmidt, Helmut, 1974; 1976 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Schmidt, Wolfgang, 1947-1948 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Schumacher, Kurt, 1952 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Schröder, Gerhard, 1954-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Suhr, Otto, 1952-1957 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Wehner, Herbert, 1963-1971 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Weichmann, Herbert, 1941; 1972-1976 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - New School for Social Research, correspondence on special programs and with other faculty members, 2.17
    - New School for Social Research. General correspondence, 1942-1973 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Peace Research Project, 1939-1940 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Institute of World Affairs, 1943-1944 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Bad Godesberg Peace Conference, 1974 June (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Ascoli, Max, 1940; 1944 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Colm, Gerhard & Hanna, 1939-1960 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - David, Henry, 1959-1963 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Deyrup, Felicia (Johnson), 1960-1971 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Everett, John R., 1966-1971 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Greenbaum, Joseph J., 1968-1976 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Greene, Murray, 1971 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Heilbroner, Robert L., 1968; 1970 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Heimann, Eduard, 1942-1967 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Hovde, Bryn J., 1945-1949 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Hula, Erich, 1943-1947 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1933-1949 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1950-1969 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1959-1967 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Kallen, Horace, 1969-1970 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Landynski, Jacob, 1970-1971 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1944-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - MacIver, Robert M., 1943-1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Mayer, Carl & Trude, 1942-1974 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Mayer, Clara, 1951-1965 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Neisser, Hans & Charlotte, 1949-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Padover, Saul K., 1950-1971 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Pekelis, Alexander H., 1944 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Salomon, Albert, 1942-1966 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Schutz, Alfred, 1958-1959 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Simons, Hans, 1934-1955 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Simons, Hans, 1956-1963 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Simons, Hans & Eva, 1964-1969 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Simons, Hans & Eva, 1970-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Speier, Hans, 1937-1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Staudinger, Hans & Else, 1935-1977 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Todd, Elizabeth, 1953-1961 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Vidich, Arthur, 1975 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - White, Howard B., 1955-1965 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Wunderlich, Frieda, 1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Correspondence with organizations, institutes, etc, 2.18
    - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1951 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (Roger Baldwin), 1946-1951 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - American Council for Emigrés in the Professions, 1975 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1944-1947 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - American Political Science Association. Annual meeting, Washington, D.C., 1939 December 28-1939 December 30 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - American Political Science Association. Annual meeting, Chicago, 1940 December 27-1940 December 30 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - American Political Science Association. Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - American Political Science Association. Round Table on Comparative War Administration, 1943 January 30 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - American Political Science Association. Round Table on A Federal Solution for Europe, 1944 January 20-1944 January 23 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - American Political Science Association. Research Committee: Beyond Relativism in Political Science, 1946-1947 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - American Political Science Association. Annual meeting, 1953 September (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)